jrailpass.com 2019-11-06

# Privacy Policy and Cookies - JRailPass

## Privacy Policy

At  we take the privacy and security of our clients very seriously. That is why we have established the following Privacy Policy where you can see clearly how we collect, share, use and store the personal information that we gather either through your purchases or digitally.

### 1\. JRailPass.com Privacy Policy

is the company responsible for data protection and management through the website www.jrailpass.com, hereinafter known as the Web.

The headquarters of , forthwith referred to as the Company, we or us, with VAT number B66394073, are located in

8 am - 5 pm on business days

with contact E-mail: info@jrailpass.com.

The following privacy policy indicates each aspect of the use and management of information transmitted to the Company via the Web.

### 2\. Ways JAPAN RAIL PASS SL Collects and Uses Personal Information

The transmission of personal data is necessary in certain transactions to obtain products and contact the Company.

Personal Data is defined as the information that either collectively with other information or individually can identify a user.

The client, henceforth known as the User, is responsible for correctly supplying their information as truthfully and accurately as possible. The Company does not take responsibility for delays, setbacks or failures resulting from invalid information supplied by Users or third parties.

In the case that a User does not wish to provide personal data or does not accept this Privacy Policy, it will not be possible for this User to purchase services or products on the Web, contact the Company or receive information from the Web.

#### 2.1. When you Communicate with JAPAN RAIL PASS SL

When a User sends us an email, calls us or pays us a visit personally, it is possible that we will store the personal information that is provided to us by the User (full name, email address, delivery address, contact phone number, etc.) with the sole aim of attending to the User’s request. The e-mail messages sent to us by Users will be stored in our email management system to allow us to track orders and requests.

We will only store personal information supplied through communication with the Web in our databases if, once the User makes a purchase or places an order, he/she explicitly requests a modification to this data. This information is stored with the sole purpose of guaranteeing that any deliveries and/or future correspondence between the User and the Company are carried out efficiently without error.

With the aim of improving our services, we may review the conversations held with our Customer Service Team in order to analyze the feedback given via email and through voluntary User survey responses.

#### 2.2. When you Buy Products from JAPAN RAIL PASS SL

In addition to personal information that is introduced through communication with the Web, the Company will store certain non-sensitive data from the payment process such as the last 4 digits of the credit/debit card used. This information is saved to be used in tracking payments in banking entities and consulting any movements referring to the User’s bank, as well as to resolve any payment issues or disputes.

Please note that all the private and financial information provided by a User will not be stored nor revealed to any third parties. Any secure details introduced will only be disclosed to the User’s personal bank and/or payment processor if they have such requirements for security reasons.

2.2.1. Japan Rail Pass

When a User purchases the Japan Rail Pass through the Web, we will collect the following personal information: full names and nationalities of passengers, travel dates, contact telephone number and email address, delivery dates and, in cases where the User decides so, the billing information for the purchase. The purpose of gathering this information is to complete a successful delivery of the order.

2.2.2. Pocket WiFi and SIM Card

When a User hires a Pocket WiFi device or a SIM card through the Web, we will collect the following personal information: collection address (accommodation in Japan), arrival flight details in Japan and complete billing details. The purpose of gathering this information is to complete a successful delivery of the order.

#### 2.3. When you Subscribe to our Newsletter

From the Web’s blog, the User has the option to subscribe to our Newsletter. In this case, we only collect the User’s email address which is stored on the page/blog provider. Occasionally we may select from these email addresses to send information that could be useful or of interest to the User.

All emails include an unsubscribe option. You can cancel your subscription at any time.

#### 2.4. Other Uses of Personal Information

We may use personal information to internally compile statistics with marketing or operational purposes, including sales reports, demographic data, User interests or other User habits or trends. We employ an internal tool that holds this information for these means (which facilitates the management of data).

### 3\. Entities with which JAPAN RAIL PASS SL Shares Personal Information

It is necessary to share personal information collected by the Company with certain entities that either work alongside the Company to allow us to fulfil services offered or deliver products purchased by the User or those that offer services to the Web to directly or indirectly improve the User experience.

#### 3.1. With Other Companies

In order to complete orders placed on the Web, there are certain other companies that need to receive personal information to be able to carry out the corresponding task. The information shared is limited to the absolutely necessary.

3.1.1. Nippon Travel Agency (NTA)

NTA is an authorised company who prints Japan Rail Pass tickets, we are one of the official distributors of the JRP. In order to be able to print the tickets and fulfil our Users’ orders, we communicate with NTA and share basic client information (full names, purchased products, if the User’s nationality is Japanese or otherwise). These are the details that are necessary to print a valid Japan Rail Pass ticket and it is the only purpose we share this information.

You can consult the Privacy Policy of [Nippon Travel Agency](http://www.ntainbound.com/policy/privacy_policy.htm) to see how they use and store this information.

3.1.2. Global Advanced Communications (GAC)

GAC is our Pocket WiFi and SIM Card distributor. So that GAC can deliver the device paid for by the client to the right place on the date specified. We share information that will allow for a successful delivery such as the product ordered and specifications, full name of recipient and hotel or accommodation address (if they so desire), flight details in case the device is to be delivered upon arrival at the airport and arrival date. As well as this, we include the User email address as it is GAC who will contact the client directly to give them all the details for delivery, tracking for shipping and any other related information with their purchase/hire or delivery.

You can consult the Privacy Policy of [Global Advanced Communications](https://www.globaladvancedcomm.com/privacy-policy/) to see how they use and store this information.

3.1.3. Delivery Companies

When a Japan Rail Pass is purchased, the client should receive a physical document printed on specific, official paper that they will then be able to proceed to exchange in Japan. The delivery information provided by the User (full name, full delivery address, contact telephone number and email) will be transmitted to our partnering delivery companies with the aim of ensuring a successful delivery of the purchased product. In these cases, we work with Fedex and UPS. On occasion and with the sole purpose of resolving shipping issues, we may share additional information that the client has previously supplied to us.

You can consult the Privacy Policy of [FedEx](http://images.fedex.com/images/us/2011crimages/CPC/FedEx_Global_Privacy_Policy.pdf) and [UPS](https://www.ups.com/us/en/help-center/legal-terms-conditions/privacy-notice.page?) to see how they use and store this information.

#### 3.2. With Digital Service Providers

Certain digital services are outsourced from the Company in order to maintain proper operations and a high quality of service to all Users of the site and clients who purchase our products.

The information we may share with these service providers is detailed below.

3.2.1. Analytics

We use third-party companies to help us to understand and analyze User behavior and client habits through platforms which organize data and allow us to extract conclusions in order to improve the User experience on the Web.

It is possible in certain cases in order to resolve, find or understand errors on the Web, that User sessions could be recorded to see how the User navigates through the Web. These recordings never transmit personal details of the User, this data is hidden by the application.

We may also use other third-party analytics service providers to obtain statistical data about our Users which help us to understand how the client navigates our Web. These are described in the Cookies Policy.

3.2.2. Email providers

We use an e-mail platform which allows us to speedily manage our reminder e-mails, offers for services which could be of interest to the User and to send our newsletter to those Users who have signed up to receive it.

3.2.3. Chat

On our Web we use a platform which allows us to easily offer attention to our clients through a chat messaging service. This platform only registers the location of the User, the IP address, the webpages they have visited and the conversation had with our customer service agents. The sole purpose of registering these details is to improve the outstanding service we offer to our Users.

You can consult the Privacy Policy of [Tawk](https://www.tawk.to/privacy-policy/), the chat platform that we employ on our Web, to see the ways in which they use and store the information gathered.

3.2.4. Blog

On our Web we use a platform to manage our blog. When a User leaves a comment, has a question or suggestion, these are registered along with the information provided such as name, email, User’s website (optional) as well as their IP address with the sole aim of offering them the best support possible.

### 4\. Right to Review, Correct, Update and Delete Personal Information

The User has the right to contact the Company at any time to request an update, correction or to review the information that they have shared with us. It is also possible at any time to delete any personal information definitively by contacting us.

Data protection for our Users is very important to us which is why we require User authentication to review, correct, update or delete personal information as only the same individual can make amendments to any personal data stored.

Email us at info@jrailpass.com for more information or to exercise this right. Or send a letter addressed to:

with Att: Data Protection.

### 5\. JAPAN RAIL PASS SL Privacy Policy for Children

Data protection for Users or relations to Users of the Web who are under 16 years of age is especially important to us and we impose a strict Privacy Policy concerning any Children’s personal information that is collected, shared or stored. Japan Rail Pass tickets can be used by children and in order to issue this tickets, it is obligatory to store certain personal data as we do with adult’s information.

Parents or Legal Guardians can contact us at any time to resolve any issues regarding this information.

#### 5.1. How we Collect and Use Information from Children

Although the Web is neither configured for use by minors nor for children to have access to make payments, we do need to collect certain information for any children who plan to travel using the Japan Rail Pass. The information collected is limited to full name, gender and nationality. This information is compulsory to be able to make use of the acquired product.

The rest of the services provided on the Web (product purchases, web navigation, blog comments, etc.) are not directed toward children under the age of 16. We ask that any under-16s abstain from using the Web or providing any personal information.

In any cases where personal information of children is collected or shared with the Company that is not entirely necessary for use of our products, it will be deleted as soon as possible and not shared under any circumstance.

#### 5.2. What Information regarding Children is Shared?

From the data collected about children, only certain information is shared with Nippon Travel Services. Of this information, the only data that is stored in their systems is the full name of the child traveling, in order to allow them to exchange the JRailPass Voucher for the Japan Rail Pass ticket.

#### 5.3. How Can Parents Access, Change or Delete Information about their Child?

Similarly to the process of exercising an adult’s right to alter, review or delete personal information that is stored by the Web, the parent or legal guardian can contact us at any time to make amendments, correct, update or eliminate personal data regarding their children.

### 6\. Security

The security of our Users’ and clients’ personal data is fundamental to us. That is why we put in place certain measures to protect any information from loss, incorrect use, circulation or alteration.

The Company is committed to ensuring that at all times there are members of our team monitoring our systems to assure that we offer the best security to our Users, employing different safeguarding processes and technical security systems.

### 7\. Retention of Personal Information

We save personal information for a total of ten years, except in cases where the law demands that we retain it for an extended period.

### 8\. Applicable Jurisdiction

The general conditions indicated in this document fall under Spanish law. Each party, with stated renounce to any other jurisdiction, will be subject to the Judges and Courts of the city of Barcelona, for the settlement of any controversy or legal dispute that might arise.

## Cookie Policy

This web uses “cookies”, own and third parties in order to better understand the user experience and personalize the online journey of the customers.

The following Cookie Policy explains the cookies used by the JRailPass Website, hereinafter referred to as the Website, owned as such by 

All Users of the Website, by accessing the content and employing the services and products available on the Website hereby confirm to accept and adhere to the Terms of Use which include the Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy as conditions of use of the Website.

### What are Cookies?

Cookies are small fragments of information which are generated by all websites to be stored on the hard disk of a User’s computer or other device with Internet connection. These are used to improve operations of different websites and facilitate the use of these with regards preferences and User habits.

When a User accesses the Website, cookies gather information that is stored and later recovered to improve and speed up the User’s session. Once the session is closed, the cookies will cease to compile information.

The memorized data recorded by cookies takes up a small space on a device’s memory and does not harm the device in anyway.

### How does JRailPass use Cookies?

On our Website, we employ our own cookies and what are known as third-party cookies to ensure an optimized user experience and facilitate the use of each stage of our Website.

There are several types of cookies which can be used to gather information to help our Users navigate and make purchases on the Website.

Such categories of cookies used include technical cookies which allow the User’s device to remember certain information to access restricted areas such as Usernames, passwords, social network accesses etc. Also, we use personalization cookies to ensure the User’s language needs are met by remembering the regional settings on a User’s browser etc. Another type of cookie that is used by the Website to constantly improve our online user experience are analytical and third-party cookies which obtain statistics and measure User behavior which in turn allow us to evaluate the quality of our services. The main third-party cookie generator is Google Analytics, the most popular online analytical system, with its headquarters in the USA. Finally, the Website also generates other third-party cookies through advertising and management of the Website, allowing the Website to build a profile of the User and personalize the offers sent to their browser.

### Accepting Cookies

Generally most browsers are configured to accept cookies as standard however the User always has the ability to refuse the use of cookies on any given website, JRailPass included.

If a User chooses to deactivate the cookies through their browser settings, this may limit their access to parts of the Website or they could lose the ability to use certain functions.

By engaging with the Website, the User acknowledges their acceptance of the use of cookies in the manner that is detailed herein as well as confirming their acceptance of the Company [Terms of Use](https://www.jrailpass.com/terms-and-conditions) and Privacy Policy.

If, at any time, you have any questions regarding the use of cookies on our Website, please do not hesitate to contact us at info@jrailpass.com.
